# ROHIT KUMAR

 $(+32) \cdot 465 \cdot 931350 \diamond \text{rohit1308k@gmail.com}$ Personal website: http://rohit13k.github.io/

#### RESEARCH INTEREST

Big Data platforms, Data Stream Mining, Graph Stream Mining and Distributed Processing, Data Security and Privacy.

#### **SUMMARY**

I am an ambitious, enthusiastic and talented individual with a keen eye for detail and a flair for new startups and projects. I have got an opportunity to work on a new initiative and take it from an internal project to a million dollar business. My objective is to work in a challenging work environment and to learn something new every day. I worked in IT industry for 6.5 years before moving to Europe to pursue my passion for research and knowledge. Currently, I am pursuing my Ph.D. in "Graph Data stream mining and distributed processing" from ULB(Brussels) and UPC(Barcelona). I have 6 publications in top conferences and 1 granted and 2 applied patents.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

ULB
PhD Candidate

August 2014 - now
Brussel, Belgium

- · 1 A\* rank, 2 A rank and 1 B rank full conference papers published.
- · Working on Graph stream mining algorithms for different use cases influence propagation or fraud detection.
- · Working on Apache GraphX and other Distributed Graph processing systems.

# Royal bank of Scotland

June 2014 - July 2014 New Delhi, India

Software Designer

· Developing high availability query systems on Oracle Coherence.

#### **Tata Consultancy Services**

April 2013 - May 2014

Assistant Consultant

Mumbai, India

- · Technical team lead for the development of an Online Assessment software.
- · Client interaction and designing new offerings for education domain.
- · Managed a team of 30 software developers.

#### **Tata Consultancy Services**

April 2011 - March 2013

IT Analyst

Mumbai, India

- · Managed the technical aspects of expanding my master's thesis from in house incubation to a million dollar business for TCS.
- · Developed and deployed the complete Eco-system of the online assessment platform in multi-tenant architecture for software as a service model.
- · Managed a team of 10 software developers.

# TCS - Tata Research Development and Design Center

April 2011 - September 2011

Researcher

Pune, India

· Worked on data privacy and data security.

## **Tata Consultancy Services**

Assistant System Engineer

Nov 2007 - March 2011 Chennai, India

- · Lead architect to develop and deploy the online assessment platform for TCS hiring throughout India.
- · Performance and Security Lead for the online assessment platform.

# JNCSAR, IISC, Bangalore

2004 - 2007

Summer Research Intern

Bangalore, India

· Did two summer(2 months) and one winter(1 month) research intern in Nanoscience.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Université Libre de Bruxelles (ULB), Belgium & Universitat Politécnica de Catalunya (UPC), Spain August 2014 - Now

- · Joint PhD in Computer Science
- · Research Topic: Graph Stream mining and distributed processing

## Chennai Mathematical Institute, India

April 2008 - March 2011

- · M.Sc in Computer Science
- · Thesis Topic: Security aspects of online Assessment platform-Touchstone

# Hindu College Delhi University, India

July 2004 - July 2007

· B.Sc(Hons) in Physics

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

**Programming** J2EE, Java, Scala, C++, R-basics

Databases MySQL, Microsoft SQL, MongoDB, Oracle Coherence

Frameworks Hadoop, Apache Spark, Apache Storm, Kafka, Struts 2, JDBC Tools SVN, CVS, github, Eclipse, RStudio, Octave, Matlab, gnuplot

# AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- FNRS-Belgian National Funds for Scientific research, Scholarship for Doctoral Research Study.
- Best Technical Lead Award in ACTion2013 in SMB iON, TCS.
- Special initiative Award by TCS in May 2013.
- Technical Excellence Award by TCS in March 2012.
- Innovation of the year award southern region in TATA Innovista 2011.
- Senior Diploma in Arts and Painting from Ankan Kala Bibhag, Ravindra Bharti University in 2006.

# PUBLICATIONS AND PATENTS

- IMaxer: A Unified System for evaluating Influence Maximization Mechanisms in Location-based Social Networks. CIKM 2017 (DEMO Paper)
- Finding simple temporal cycles in an interaction network. ECML/PKDD 2017 (Workshop paper)
- Activity-Driven Influence Maximization in Social Networks. ECML/PKDD 2017 (Nectar Track)
- Cost Model for Pregel on GraphX. ADBIS 2017
- Information Propagation in Interaction Networks. EDBT 2017
- Location Influence in Location-based Social Networks. WSDM 2017
- Maintaining Sliding-Window Neighborhood Profiles in Interaction Networks. ECML/PKDD 2015
- System and method for automated competency assessment (US8915744) Granted
- Secured Computer Based Assessment (US20140186812A1) Applied
- Customized question paper generation (US20130084554) Applied